theblogmaven.com 2016-11-04

# Privacy Policy | The Blog Maven

Maven Media, LLC (“Maven Media”) operates several websites including theblogmaven.com and bmavendesign.com. It is Maven Media’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Maven Media collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Maven Media’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Maven Media’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Maven Media may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Maven Media also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on theblogmaven.com. Maven Media only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Maven Media’s websites choose to interact with Maven Media in ways that require Maven Media to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Maven Media gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a course at theblogmaven.com to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Maven Media – by purchasing access to our courses, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Maven Media collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Maven Media. Maven Media does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Maven Media may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Maven Media may monitor comments on theblogmaven.com site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Maven Media may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Maven Media does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Maven Media discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Maven Media’s behalf or to provide services available at Maven Media’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Maven Media’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Maven Media will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Maven Media discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Maven Media believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Maven Media, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Maven Media website and have supplied your email address, Maven Media may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Maven Media and our products. We primarily use our main blog and opt-in email list to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Maven Media takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Maven Media uses cookies to help Maven Media identify and track visitors, their usage of Maven Media website, and their website access preferences. Maven Media visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Maven Media’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Maven Media’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If Maven Media, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Maven Media goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Maven Media may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Maven Media and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Maven Media may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Maven Media’s sole discretion. Maven Media encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Portions of this Policy were reproduced with grateful acknowledgement of [Automattic Inc.](http://automattic.com/privacy/) via Creative Commons Sharealike license.
